<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>raf's random writings</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/</link><description>Random ramblings by a computer engineer</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 18:41:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Booting Raspberry Pi Root in read-only</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2013-06-02-booting-raspberry-pi-in-readonly.html</link><description>So last week a lot of people around here were looking into how to boot a raspberry pi with
the SD card partition in read only mode - this came after a couple of annoying
data losses.</description></item><item><title>C(99) preprocessor tricks</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2013-05-30-c-preprocessor-tricks.html</link><description>On account of a recent project i've been working on, I had the chance to
program a bit of C, something I have not done in a while. 
This is turn led me to think about macros, and how some of the features in C99
came together to help me a bit.</description></item><item><title>Open attachments in Mutt with your desktop apps</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2013-01-07-mutt-and-xdg.html</link><description>Yes I'm a proud Mutt user, say what you will about user interfaces but no mail
client in the known universe can compare to the awesomeness of Mutt.</description></item><item><title>OBEXFTP and the elusive error code 64</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2012-10-23-obexftp-error-64.html</link><description>I was trying to push some files into my Nokia this morning and failed miserably at it ...</description></item><item><title>Agile diagrams with seqdiag</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2012-05-09-agile-digrams-with-seqdiag.html</link><description>If you happen to work on research, you'll find that diagrams drawing takes a big chunk of your time.
And even worse after several hours carefully drawing your diagram, you come to realise two things:</description></item><item><title>Portable Vim settings</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2012-02-20-portable-vim.html</link><description>Several people have acquired the habit of keeping their Vim settings under version control and sharing those settings as git/mercurial repositories.
Generally people do this for three reasons:</description></item><item><title>Development stack choices</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2011-11-04-development-stack.html</link><description>A while ago I was having a discussion with some colleagues about which development tools do you use, for each job.
The end result, three diagrams that more or less resume my usual approach to choosing development tools.</description></item><item><title>git workflow: pushing to multiple repositories in sync</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2011-10-27-git-workflow-pushing-to-multiple-repos.html</link><description>Recently I've been keeping an eye out for a solution to keep multiple git repositories in sync.
I've already discussed mirroring repositories in a previous post.
But in this case what I was looking for was the ability to push branches into multiple remote repositories, in one command.</description></item><item><title>Python awesomeness in a Flask</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2011-08-28-python-flask.html</link><description>While I was working on updating blogpit, I discovered this wonderful web microframework called Flask. 
Naturally it is python and of course it is awesome.
I was immediately attracted to Flask for two reasons: First it has a lot in common with Django, and second it strives to be simple.</description></item><item><title>The Magic backup script</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2011-05-24-the-magic-backup-script.html</link><description>After looking high and low for a decent backup application I ended up 
giving up, and making my own bash script using rsync. I'm highly dependant
on client initiated remote backups, and it seems there are not many solutions
like that out there.</description></item><item><title>Git Workflow: obsessing over data</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2011-02-08-git-mirror-workflow.html</link><description>Don't panic, this is not yet another Internet post on how should you use git, well
it actually is, but only slightly. So on Monday I was stressing with some co-workers
that they should commit often, in small incremental changes (etc, etc, common sense and
puppies). But at the same time I was also annoying someone to commit and push a 
considerable changeset, for fear of disk corruption, which happened before.</description></item><item><title>2 days with Android</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2011-01-14-two-days-with-android.html</link><description>After being annoyed with some show-stopping bugs at work, I decided to take two days
out of my life and tackle a major Bluetooth related BUG() we had in our Android application. 
Being the first time I tried to develop for android I was concerned I would have to use 
Eclipse, and loose my Vim-powered productivity. </description></item><item><title>Slides with inkscapeslide</title><link>http://ruiabreu.org/2010-11-12-slides-with-inkscape.html</link><description>I've been growing fond of using inkscape for drawing content for my slides.
Figures, sequence diagrams and weird charts all end up going through inkscape,
either drawn from scratch or just for some graphical fixes before they end up
on the final slides.</description></item></channel></rss>